Byrd Howell Granger papers, 1945-1990 (bulk 1956-1975)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series VI: Audiovisual, c. 1950-1990
  - Motion Pictures, c. 1950-1955
    - Alaska ferrying trip, (See also Box 3/Folder 15 for narrative account and Box 9/Folder 5 for slides). (16mm, color, 7" reel). c. 1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - See 1-2. (16mm, color, 7" reel). (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Camping trip in Grand Canyon area, (16mm, color, 2 7/8'' reel). 1954 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Fishing trip, (16mm, color, 2 7/8" reel). 1953 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Grand Canyon and Havasupai by helicopter, (16mm, color, 3 5/8'' reel). No Date (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Granger carrying rocks, (16mm, b/w, 2 7/8" reel). 1954 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Granger's Tucson Home: Construction, (16mm, color, 2 7/8" reel). 1955? (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Granger's Tucson Home: Construction, (16mm, color, 2 7/8'' reel). 1955 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Granger's Tucson Home - Construction, (16mm, color, 2 7/8" reel). 1955 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Granger's Tucson Home: Construction, (16mm, color, 2 7/8" reel). 1955 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Granger's Tucson Home: Construction, (16mm, color, 2 7/8'' reel). 1962? (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - "Red Feather Magic", (16mm, b/w, sound, 7" reel). No Date (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Rodeo (Fiesta de los Vaqueros?) and trail ride in high desert area, (16mm, b/w, 7" reel). c. 1950 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Tucson Parades and Oak Creek Canyon and Sedona, (16mm, b/w, and color, 7" reel). c. 1950 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Video, 1970s-1980s
    Video tapes of one public speech and two television appearances by Granger.
    - "Arizona Natives and Native Plants" - Desert Botanical Gardens Docents Meeting, (VHS, color). late 1980s (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - "Tucson Today with Mort Beach" - On Beliefs Concerning Evil, (U-Matic, black and white). 1970s (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Tucson Today with Mort Beach" - On Lost Mines in Arizona, (U-Matic, black and white). 1976 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Cassette Audio, 1969-1980
    Oral histories, speeches, interviews and other recordings made by or for Granger. Highlights include a recording of Granger and students of the Folklore and Cultural Awareness program speaking about the program and its effectiveness. Also of note are two tapes of an oral history interview with a Colorado pioneer woman.
    - Conversation with man and woman (Beaudry?) regarding Granger's house, hobbies, and other topics, side 2 only. No Date (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Cookie Hanson: Oral correspondence to Granger and Isabella Breasted. Oct. 25, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Folklore and Cultural Awareness Program: Granger speaking about. 1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Material Culture: Granger interviewing Jane Adams. No Date (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "National Geographic Society Food Customs", (See also Box 5/Folder 7). No Date (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - National Place Name Survey: Granger dictation. No Date (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Oral History: Dr. & Mrs. Gennady Platoff in San Antonio, Texas talking about family and world travels. 1970 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Oral History: Mrs. Miles - Pioneer woman talking about early life in Colorado. February 13, 1969 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Oral History: Mrs. Miles - Pioneer woman talking about early life in Colorado. 1969 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Random Notes on Mayan Folklore" - Granger speech at Maya Study Group. April 1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Reel Audio, 1970s
    Primarily speeches given and collected by Granger. Music and correspondence reels are also included.
    - "Apache Culture" - Speech by Billy Kane, (7" reel). May 1970 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Corridos performed by University of Arizona student Hector Manuel Martinez Soto. Song list included, (5" reel). April 20, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - "Kachinas and the Law of the Hopi" - Granger speech at National Education Secretaries Association Conference in Tucson, (7" reel). July 24, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - "Papago Legends" - as told by members of the Papago (now Tohono O'odham), (5" reel). No Date (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Unknown Female Correspondent: Oral correspondence to Granger, Side 2 only (5" reel). No Date (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Witchcraft and Other Folklore Topics: Granger speech at the Palmdale School in Phoenix, Arizona. Children also tell stories, (5" reel). No Date (Box 13, Folder 6)